CP, this is Alpha 2.
指挥所，这里是阿尔发2号
Nothing unusual to report at Point 1.
1号位置目前无异状
Alpha 2, this is CP.
阿尔发2号，这里是指挥所
Continue your observation mission.
请继续执行监视任务
An emergency Kaiju alert has just been issued. I repeat...
紧急怪兽警报已发布，重复一次...
...and Isogo wards in Yokohama City, Kanagawa Prefecture.
以及矶子区这三个区域 已发布紧急怪兽警报
Citizens in the designated areas are to seek refuge in a shelter immediately.
位于这些区域的民众，请尽速前往避难所
The epicenter's projected route is...
关于震央的动向预测...
Target is currently en route from Yatobashi to Yamashita-cho.
目标正从谷户桥往山下町方向移动
Its estimated body length is 60 meters. Fortitude 3.5. Over.
推测全长60米，怪兽规模为3.5
No one on thermals within a 3 kilometer radius.
三公里范围内未侦测到热源
Roger.
收到
All units, open fire.
所有军机开始射击
I repeat. Open fire.
重复一次，开始射击
Roger. Luring target to the TO.
收到，将目标引导至作战区
Fire.
发射
Will we succeed in getting its attention?
有办法成功吓阻它吗？
Which division will come, you think?
不知道会派出哪个部队呢？
Since this is Yokohama, it'll be the Third Division.
横滨的话就是第3部队吧
Man, they got its guts over everything!
竟然喷得到处都是
Looks like it'll be overtime for me for a while.
看来得加班一阵子了
Okay, time to get to work.
好了，开工吧
Yes, sir!
好
The members of the Third Division have successfully defeated the Kaiju,
第3部队成功讨伐怪兽
and they return to raucous cheers from the citizens.
市民正以热情掌声迎接队员们
They have once again taken down a Kaiju with no casualties.
第3部队再度达成了零伤者的成绩
She's so awesome!
太棒了
These cheers are a sign of the people's gratitude!
让我们以这些欢呼向他们致谢
Hey, get some footage of the victims, too.
别忘了拍受害者的画面哦
Oh, sorry.
啊，抱歉
Come give me a report when you're done!
-之后再跟我回报 -知道了
After all the other battles are over, our battle begins.
我们的战役在一切落幕后才会开始
Nobody's here to cheer us on.
不会有人关注我们
Nobody's particularly grateful, anyway.
也没有人会特别感谢我们
But this is our...
但这就是我们...
unsung battle against the Kaiju.
与怪兽之间的不起眼的战役
KAFKA HIBINO
（日比野卡夫卡）
Kafka, Izumo Tech says they want a sample.
卡夫卡，出云科技说想要一点样本
Thanks.
谢咯
I can't cut through this! The fat's jamming the saw!
不行，油脂卡着切不下去
Bring me the heat chainsaw!
麻烦拿电热锯给我
Sure.
好的
Hey, don't start lifting that yet!
喂！那还不能吊起来
Ow...
好痛啊
Over here! Bring a stretcher!
快拿担架过来
Don't worry. It only got on your skin.
别担心，只是伤到表皮而已
I've had it happen to me a bunch of times.
我也受伤好几次了
Make sure you file for workers' comp!
回去记得申请职灾给付啊
Will do!
我会的
Things always get messy when the Third Division's involved.
第3部队参与的现场果然乱糟糟
Hard to tell what's organs and what's not.
很难分辨哪些是内脏
Anyway... do they really expect us to finish this by the end of the week?
不过话说回来，这周内真的处理得完吗？
Kafka, got a new job for you.
卡夫卡，你的负责区域有变动
We have an opening elsewhere on-site.
我们这边现在缺一个人
Where?
哪里？
The intestines.
是肠道
I've already got permission from management.
-我不要！ -已经获得批准了，走吧
Have fun!
节哀顺变
I've heard people talking about it, but is intestine work that bad?
我是有听过传闻 但处理肠道真的很难熬吗？
Think about what's in those intestines, and then you tell me.
你想想肠子里都装些什么，就该知道了吧
Every time you get stuck on intestine duty...
处理肠道的那一天...
it takes a while before you're ready to eat again.
就会好一阵子吃不下饭
I'm so tired!
累死我了
That baby panda was so cute!
熊猫宝宝真是可爱啊
I can't wait to see it grown up!
它们的成长真令人期待
I can still smell it...
鼻子还残留着那股味道
And now, tonight's feature story.
接下来是特辑
Today, the Kaiju that appeared in Yokohama was defeated
今天有怪兽突然在横滨出现
And the division's leader is none other than the famous Captain Mina Ashiro.
率领队员的就是亚白米娜队长
Not only is she a captain at the young age of 27,
她年仅27岁，不只当上队长
she's also defeated several hundred Kaiju.
讨伐的怪兽更多达数百只
Let's wipe out all the Kaiju together!
我们一起消灭所有怪兽吧
Her cool, elegant demeanor makes her the most popular of all the captains!
再加上她沉稳凛然的氛围 让她的人气在所有队长之中名列前茅
They say she's in the running to be corps commander, too.
有望成为未来的师团长候补
She's definitely one to keep an eye on.
今后的发展令人瞩目
How'd I wind up on this side of things?
我为什么是在这里啊？
Just don't think about it!
别再想了
Cleaning up is an important job! I'm helping society!
清扫也是有所贡献的重要工作啊
I get to live in a nice apartment and eat whatever I want!
我住在不错的房子，吃着自己喜欢的食物
Isn't that good enough?
这样就够了啊
God, my head hurts...
头好痛
It's because of that damn news story.
可恶，都是那个特辑害的
Morning...
-早安 -他来了
-I'll go get things ready. -Thanks.
-我先去准备了 -嗯
Morning, Kafka.
卡夫卡，早啊
We've got a new part-timer starting today. This is Ichikawa-kun.
这是今天开始来打工的市川
He says he's aiming to join the Defense Force!
听说他想加入防卫队哦
RENO ICHIKAWA
（市川雷诺）
This guy was once like you!
这家伙以前也想进防卫队呢
He gave up, though, and now he's part of the furniture here!
不过后来他放弃梦想 现在已经是这里的老鸟了
Well, this sucks...
太糟糕了吧
Toku-san... You're freaking the new kid out.
德哥，你这样会让他很难回应啦
Why?
为什么？
Why'd you give up?
你为什么放弃了？
I did do my best, you know, but...
我也不是没努力过
No matter how good you are, there's always somebody better.
但该说是一山还有一山高吗？
You'll understand when you're older.
等你年纪大了就会懂...
I won't.
我不懂
'Cause I'll never give up.
我不会放弃
So I won't know until the day I die.
所以到死都不会懂的
Not that I'd even want to.
我也不想懂
I'll go change.
我去换衣服了
Huh... I thought you and him would get along.
唉呀，我还以为你们会很合得来
That's not fair!
太不公平了吧
There's nothing I could've said that wouldn't make me sound like a loser!
那种问题我怎么回答 都只会显得自己很凄惨而已啊
Is giving up that bad?
放弃真的有这么糟糕吗？
-Hey! -Okay, let's get started.
好了，开工咯
Miike's team can stay on bone cleaning duty.
三池小组继续清洗骨头
Get the important ones ready for Izumo Tech.
没损害的部分要交给出云科技
On it!
好
Yoshimura's team can start taking apart the legs.
吉村小组负责解体脚部
Dump all of it.
-这边就全数废弃 -好
New kid, you're on intestines.
新人，你负责肠道
-Follow me. -Yes, sir.
-跟我来 -好的
You too, Kafka. Follow me.
卡夫卡，你也过来处理肠道
Me too?!
我也是哦？
Two days in a row!
这样我连续两天了耶
You're good with intestine work, though.
因为你很会处理肠道嘛
Damn it! Fine, I'll do it!
可恶，我做就是了
He complains, but he never says no.
抱怨归抱怨，他还是会乖乖照辨
He would've done a great job in the Defense Force if he'd passed.
如果当初他有考上 应该会是个不错的防卫队员吧
You serious?
真的吗？
Yeah, he's definitely feeling it.
是不是很难受啊？
And so am I.
我自己也是啦
You...
我说你啊
Is that lunch box all the food you brought?
你只带了那个便当吗？
I don't feel up to eating it.
我应该吃不下了
Yeah, I bet.
我想也是
Here.
-拿去 -什么啊？
You can have it.
这给你
You need to get something in your stomach,
多少要吃点东西，不然你撑不过下午
I'm fine...
-我没关系... -还有
And these. You can have these, too.
这个也给你
These help a lot.
有了这个会好很多
I can't understand what you're saying, but I really don't need those.
我不知道你在说什么 但我真的不需要那个东西
Quit playing coy and put them in your nose!
跟我客气什么，你塞看看嘛
Stop it! Senpai, really...
前辈，你这是职权骚扰...
You're all responsible for carrying your own stuff.
自己的东西要自己拿走哦
Good work today!
辛苦咯
Good work today.
辛苦了
See you tomorrow.
我们先走了
Sure, goodnight.
嗯，辛苦啦
Well, at least the smelliest part of the job is over.
最臭的地方已经处理完了吧
Senpai.
前辈
Oh, Ichikawa.
市川啊
What, did you come to get back at me for what I did at lunch?
怎么？你是想报中午的仇吗？
Thanks to you...
托你的福...
Thanks to you, I made it through my first day.
我才能撑过第一天
Thank you.
谢谢你
Goodnight.
那我走了
Oh, and...
对了
They're raising the age limit to 32.
年龄限制会放宽为未满33岁哦
For applicants to the Defense Force.
防卫队的报考资格
Not enough young people anymore, apparently.
似乎是因为少子化的影响
I can't tell you what to do with your life, of course...
虽然说这是你的人生，你高兴就好
But when you talked about giving up, you looked so sad.
但我看你提到放弃的时候 表情看起来好像很落寞
Of course, I really don't care at all.
不过我真的不在乎
So if I'm wrong, you can just give up and I won't care.
如果是我误会了，你就尽管放弃吧
Goodnight!
再见
Ichikawa!
市川
Thanks.
谢啦
You're a lot nicer than I thought you were.
没想到你人还满不错的嘛
I told you, I really don't——
我就跟你说了不是这样...
Senpa——
前辈...
A Yoju?
是余兽？
Ichikawa, run!
市川，你快逃
Get as far away from here as you can!
全速奔跑远离这里
Once you're sure you're safe, call it in!
到了安全的地方再通报防卫队
You can't fight this thing alone!
-但前辈你一个人... -就算两个人也没用
You want to join the Defense Force, right?
你不是要当防卫队员吗？
So why would you let yourself get killed here?!
怎么可以死在这里！
Over here! I'm the one you want!
过来这边啊
There!
就是那里
Whew!
很好
Now it can't follow me...
这样就...
Damn it all!
可恶！
It's all gone...
全部都被摧毁了
Your place, my place, our school...
米娜你家、我家跟学校
Yeah...
嗯
I'll get you for this, Kaiju!
我不原谅那些怪兽
I was so close to beating Guramon!
我的《古拉梦》差点就要完全破关了
That's what you're sad about?
你难过的是那个吗？
I'm sad that Miiko died.
我难过是因为咪可死掉
Miiko, your calico cat?
咪可是你那只三花猫，对吧？
I'm going to join the Defense Force!
我要成为防卫队员
That's dumb. You're just a little kid!
你这个小鬼头在说什么啊
You're in elementary school too, Kafka!
卡夫卡，你自己不也是个小学生？
FOR MIIKO KAFKA, MINA
（悼念咪可，卡夫卡与米娜）
All right...
那么...
Let's see who can be a cooler Defense Force officer!
我们来比赛，看谁能成为帅气的防卫队员
Let's wipe out all the Kaiju together!
我们一起消灭所有怪兽吧
Damn it all!
可恶
It wasn't supposed to be like this!
事情不该是这样的
I ain't afraid of you, Kaiju!
怪兽又怎样？
Aim for the leg...
瞄准脚部
Aim...
瞄准...
How did it come to this?
为什么会变成这样？
Let's see who can be a cooler Defense Force officer!
我们来比赛，看谁能成为帅气的防卫队员
Ichikawa...
市川？
You idiot!
你这笨蛋，为什么？
I called it in!
我已经通报防卫队了
That's not what I meant!
我不是在问你这个！
If I left you to die here...
如果我就这样丢下前辈你不管
I'd never make it in the Defense Force!
那我绝对无法成为防卫队员
WE REGRET TO INFORM YOU THAT...
（不合格）
Damn it...
可恶
JAPAN DEFENSE FORCE RECRUITING NOW
（日本防卫队，招聘中）
I'm so powerless...
为什么我这么无能为力？
Nothing's changed at all!
从以前到现在都是这样
I can't protect anything. Not my game console, or my friend's cat...
不管是自己的游戏机，还是朋友的猫
Or even the new kid at my job!
就连一个后辈也保护不了
Damn it!
可恶！
Target down.
已击破目标
We have wounded.
似乎有人受伤
Initiating rescue operations.
接着将转为救护伤者
Igarashi. Takaragi. Take care of the wounded.
（日本防卫队第3部队）
Everyone else, follow me.
其他人跟着我去搜索是否还有余兽
You okay?
你还好吧？
Don't move. Just stay there.
你别动，保持这个姿势就好
Mina's incredible...
米娜好厉害啊
She took down that scary thing in less than a second...
那么吓人的怪兽，她一瞬间就解决了
She's left me in the dust.
她已经到达我遥不可及的境界了
Senpai!
前辈
Y-Yeah?
什么事？
When that Kaiju showed up and you told me to run away...
怪兽出现后，你叫我逃跑
If you hadn't saved my life then,
那时候要不是你救了我
I would've died today.
我今天早就死了
You were so cool.
你真的超帅气的
Let's see who can be a cooler Defense Force officer!
我们来比赛，看谁能成为帅气的防卫队员
You really should think about joining the Defense Force.
你真的应该去当防卫队员才对
I mean, it's your call. Not my problem.
不过那是你的自由 你怎样决定，我都无所谓
Yeah...
对啊
I can't just keep running forever!
我到底还要视而不见到什么时候？
Thanks, Ichikawa.
市川，谢谢你
You really are a nice guy.
你果然是个好人嘛
I don't think there's anything wrong with giving up...
我不觉得放弃是一件坏事
But it's not good to lie to yourself.
但欺骗自己并不是一件好事
I'm going to give the Defense Force another go——
我决定再次立志成为防卫...
Found you.
找到你了
A Kai... A Kai——
怪...
Senpai?
前辈？
Are your wounds bothering you?
你伤口很痛吗？
Senpai!
前辈！
What?!
什么？
Ichikawa! It's me! It's me!
市川，是我啊
Don't freak out like that, please!
你别吓成这样啊
AH.
（啊）
He's calling you in.
他在通报防卫队
Let's get out of here, Senpai!
前辈，快逃啊
EPISODE 1: THE MAN WHO BECAME A KAIJU
（第1集：变成怪兽的男人）
If you encounter a Kaiju, the first thing you do is target the legs.
遇到怪兽时，就要先攻击它的脚
You bind it so it can't move...
把脚绑起来，让它动弹不得
I get a little scared.
有点可怕耶
Of what?
哪里可怕了？
When I imagine fighting a Kaiju that's so much bigger than I am.
想到要跟 比自己大好几倍的怪兽战斗，我就...
Don't worry!
你放心
Whenever you get scared...
不管什么时候...
I'll always be right by your side!
我都会陪在你身边的
Liar.
骗子
Yes?
是
A Kaiju has appeared at Yokohama South General Hospital?
横滨南综合医院出现怪兽？
Yes.
好的
No.
不会
It's fine.
没问题
I'll get my team ready,
我马上派队员出动
and we'll eliminate it.
进行扑杀